Finding Aid for Roy A. Rappaport Papers 1959-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Speeches and Lectures
  - Conference of the National Association for Environmental Education-Keynote Address-"Adaptation and Maladaptation in the Evolution of Culture, Technology, and Society", 1983 (Box 7)
  - Eastern Michigan University-Symposium on Educating the Information Society, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Annenberg Scholars Conference on Communication and Collective Memory, University of Southern California, 1986 (Box 7)
  - "Alumni on Society Islands", March 25, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Indiana University
    - "Logos, Liturgy and the Evolution of Humanity", October 20, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Seminar on Sanctity, October 21, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Skomp Distinguished Lecture-"The Construction of Time and Eternity in Ritual", October 1986 (Box 7)
  - "Logos, Liturgy and the Evolution of Humanity", 1986; 1987; 1990 (Box 7)
  - Culture and Personality Symposium, 1987 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan Seminar-"Religion in the Evolution of Humanity", 1988 (Box 7)
  - ICAES Symposium-Evolutionary Ecology and the Human Condition-"Logos, Liturgy and the Evolution of Humanity", 1988 (Box 7)
  - American Ethnological Society spring meeting-"The Construction of Time and Eternity in Ritual", April 8, 1989 (Box 7)
  - American Anthropological Association-Symposium Assessing Developments in Anthropology-"Humanity's Evolution and Anthropology's Future", 1989 (Box 7)
  - Soviet Lecture-"Humanity's Evolution and Anthropology's Future", 1989 (Box 7)
  - American Anthropological Association-Symposium on Assessing Developments in Anthropology-"Law and Meaning, Discovery and Construction", 1989 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan-Population-Environment Dynamics Seminar, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan-Anthropology Department-"On Mead", 1991 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan-Walgreen Inaugural Lecture-"Misunderstanding, Meaning and the Breaking of the World", 1992 (Box 7)
  - Colloquium on Teaching Race and Racism, 1992 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan-"On Trust", 1992 (Box 7)
  - American Anthropological Association-"Comments for Bridging the Human Dimensions of Global Environmental Issues", 1992 (Box 7)
  - "Veracity, Verity and Verum in Liturgy" Symposium on Reclaiming our Rites, Notre Dame Center for Pastoral Liturgy 1992 and North American Academy of Liturgy Annual Meeting, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Ritual Studies Conference, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Society for Ecological Restoration, 1994 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan-"Art and Ritual", 1995 (Box 7)
  - Society for Applied Anthropology-Session on Natural Resources and Societal Values, "Risk and the Human Environment", 1995 (Box 7)
  - "On Evil: The Destruction of Meaning and the Disruption of the World", 1995 (Box 7)
  - "The World Turned Inside Out", 1995 (Box 8)
  - University of Michigan-Conference on Information and Meaning at the Millennium-"What Will be Human", 1996 (Box 8)
- Classes and Teaching
  The Classes and Teaching series includes syllabi, exams, lectures, and notes from several classes Rappaport taught. The majority of the records come from his time at the University of Michigan, but there is also some material from his early teaching experience as a doctoral student at Columbia, as well as from a few of the institutions where he was a guest lecturer. The care and thought with which he approached his students is evident in this series. It is also possible, through various versions of lectures, to trace how Rappaport's presentation of specific ideas changed over time. The student papers included in this collection demonstrate the level of interaction Rappaport had with his students and the respect he had for their ideas.
  - Columbia
    - Ethnography and Political Relations, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Seminar on Political Relations on the Island of Tikopia (Polynesia), circa 1960s (Box 8)
  - University of Michigan
    - Anthropology 101 "Introduction to Anthropology"
      - Syllabus and Study Aid, 1966 (Box 8)
      - Study Aid, 1970 (Box 8)
      - Syllabi, Exams, Evaluations, and Notes, 1983-1985; 3 folders (Box 8)
      - Lectures
        - Lecture 1-Introduction, 1972-1985 (Box 8)
        - Lecture 2-Emergence of Anthropology, 1983-1985; undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 3-Concept of Evolution, 1984-1985; undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 4-Biological Evolution, undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 5-Evolution of Life and the Primates, undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 6-Primate Social Organization, 1983-1985; undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 7-Hunters and Gatherers, circa 1983-1984; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
        - Lecture 8-Hominoid Evolution, undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 9-Communication and Language, 1983 (Box 8)
        - Lecture 12-Race, 1983; 1985 undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 13-Evolution of Culture, undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 14-Paleolithic, Mesolithic, and Neolithic, undated (Box 8)
        - Lecture 18-Transition Ecology, undated (Box 8)
        - Lectures 19-20-Tsembaga, 1983 undated (Box 8)
        - Lectures 21-22-Economics, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
        - Lectures 23-25-Social Organization and Kinship, 1983-1985; undated (Box 8)
        - Language and Culture, 1983 (Box 8)
        - Food Cultivation, circa 1980s (Box 8)
        - Tribal Design, 1985 (Box 8)
        - Political Organization and Social Control, circa 1980s (Box 8)
        - Religion, circa 1983-1984 (Box 8)
        - States and Civilization, Anthropology in the Modern World, circa 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - Anthropology 216-Lecture-Development and Adaptive Structure, circa 1970s (Box 8)
    - Anthropology 448/Religion 452 "Anthropology of Religion"
      - Syllabi, Exams, Evaluations, and Notes, 1982-1995; undated; 9 folders (Box 8)
    - Anthropology 448/Religion 452 "Anthropology of Religion" (cont.) (Box 9)
      - Lectures
        - First Day and Lecture II, 1982-1995; 2 folders (Box 9)
        - "The Ritual Form", circa 1980s-1994 (Box 9)
        - "Self-Referential (Indexical) Messages", circa 1982-1995 (Box 9)
        - "Word and Act", circa 1985-1995 (Box 9)
        - "Informative Acts", circa 1980s-1990s (Box 9)
        - "The Dimensions of Liturgical Order", circa 1994 (Box 9)
        - "Sanctity", circa 1980s (Box 9)
        - "Myth", circa 1980s-1995 (Box 9)
        - "The Holy in Human Adaptation", circa 1990-1995 (Box 9)
        - "Origins of the Numinous", circa 1980s (Box 9)
    - Religion 404 "Seminar in Comparative Religion"
      - Syllabus and Notes, 1978 (Box 9)
      - Class Outline, Exam, and Notes, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Anthropology 450/Religion 404 "Logos and Liturgy"
      - Syllabus, Evaluations, and Notes, 1985 (Box 9)
      - Syllabus, Exams, and Notes, 1986 (Box 9)
      - Lectures, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
      - Lecture Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - Anthropology 450 and 458/Religion 404 and 402 "Religious Experience"-Syllabi and Lecture Notes, 1991; 1995; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Anthropology 450/Religion 404-Exam and Lecture Notes, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Anthropology 450/Religion 404 "The Theory and Practice of Evil in the 20th and 21st Centuries", 1994; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Anthropology 452 "Anthropology of Religion I"
      - Syllabi, Exams, and Notes, 1974-1980; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Lecture-"Liturgical Order", circa 1977 (Box 9)
    - Anthropology 453 "Anthropology of Religion II"
      - Syllabus and Notes, 1971 (Box 9)
      - Lectures-"Religion and Adaptation", circa 1970s (Box 9)
      - Lectures and Handouts, circa 1970s (Box 10)
      - Lectures, circa 1971; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Anthropology 501-Lecture, September 1979 (Box 10)
    - Anthropology 510
      - Syllabi, Notes, and Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      - Exams, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      - Lectures
        - Introduction, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
        - 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Syllabus, Evaluations, and Notes, 1967 (Box 10)
      - Lectures
        - Culture and Biology, 1967 (Box 10)
        - The Subject Matter of Anthropology, 1967 (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous Notes, 1967 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus, Exam, and Notes, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Course Planning, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Lecture-Environmental Factors in Anthropological Explanation, circa 1969 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus, Exam, and Notes, 1970 (Box 10)
      - Lecture Notes and Lectures, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Anthropology 510 and Anthropology 511-Lecture Notes, circa 1970-1971 (Box 10)
    - Anthropology 511
      - Lecture Notes, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus, 1966 (Box 10)
      - Lecture Notes, circa 1966 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus and Lecture Notes, 1967 (Box 10)
      - Lecture-Ecology, circa 1967 (Box 10)
      - Lecture-"Ritual, Sanctity and Communication", 1967 (Box 10)
      - Lectures on Religion and Exam, 1968 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus and Lecture Notes, 1970 (Box 10)
      - Notes on Sahlins Lectures, 1970 (Box 10)
      - Lectures
        - On the Study of the Primitive, 1970 (Box 10)
        - Process and Structure, 1970 (Box 10)
        - Authority and Power, Political Relations, 1970 (Box 10)
        - Ecology, circa 1970 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus, Exam, and Lecture Notes, 1971 (Box 10)
      - Lectures
        - Religion, 1971 (Box 10)
        - Discussion of Bateson, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Anthropology 526 "Theory and Practice in Ethnology"
      - Syllabus and Course Planning, 1984 (Box 10)
      - Lecture Notes, 1984 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus and Lecture Notes, 1985 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus and Notes, 1986 (Box 10)
      - Lecture-"Introduction", 1984-1986 (Box 10)
      - Lecture Notes, 1986 (Box 10)
      - Lecture-On the Study of Religion in Early Anthropology, 1991 (Box 10)
      - Syllabus and Lecture, 1993 (Box 10)
      - Lecture-Early Anthropology, circa 1990s (Box 10)
    - Anthropology 527 "Traditions in Ethnology II"
      - Syllabi, Exams, and Notes, 1987-1991; 1996; 5 folders (Box 10)
      - Lectures
        - Introduction, 1991; 1996 (Box 11)
        - On Gregory Bateson, 1988; 1990-1991; 1996 (Box 11)
        - British Structural-Functionalism, 1990 (Box 11)
        - Kinship, 1990 (Box 11)
        - Ecology, 1988; 1990-1992 (Box 11)
        - Environmental Anthropology, 1996 (Box 11)
        - On Levi Strauss, 1990-1991; 1996 (Box 11)
        - Symbolic and Interpretive Anthropology, 1990-1991; 1996 (Box 11)
        - On the Postmodern, 1988; 1990-1991 (Box 11)
        - Practice, History, and Anthropology (Box 11)
        - Conclusion, 1988; 1990; 1996 (Box 11)
      - Other Notes
        - Notes on Dresh Lectures, circa 1990 (Box 11)
        - Notes on Tom Fricke Lectures, 1990 (Box 11)
        - Notes on Sherry Ortner and Ray Kelly Lectures, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Anthropology 541 "Anthropology, Ecology, and the Environment"
      - Syllabi, 1992; 1994 (Box 11)
      - Lectures, Exams, Notes, and Handouts, 1992; 1994; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Anthropology 576-Pacific Course
      - Exams, Lectures, and Notes, 1968 (Box 11)
      - Notes-Polynesian Populations and their Ecologies, circa 1968 (Box 11)
      - Lectures, circa 1968
        - Lecture 1-People of the Pacific (Box 11)
        - Lectures 2-5-Pacific Geography (Box 11)
        - Lecture 6-Biological Characteristics of Pacific Populations (Box 11)
        - Lecture 7-Pacific Languages (Box 11)
        - Food Plants (Box 11)
        - Pacific Archaeology (Box 11)
        - Introduction to Polynesia (Box 11)
        - Maring Political Organization (Box 11)
        - Introduction to Melanesia (Box 11)
        - Coastal Melanesia (Box 11)
        - Polynesia vs. Melanesia (Box 11)
        - The New Guinea Highlands (Box 11)
        - Lecture Notes-Marshall Sahlins (Box 11)
        - Lecture Notes-Highland Notes (Box 11)
        - Ritual Regulation (Box 11)
        - Big Men (Box 11)
        - Loose Structure (Box 11)
        - Pacific Island Ecosystems (Box 11)
      - Manuscript-The Ecology of Polynesian Societies, circa 1960s (Box 11)
    - Anthropology 589/624 "Ecological Approaches in Cultural Anthropology/Prehistoric Human Ecology"
      - Reading Lists and Notes, 1968 (Box 11)
      - Ecology Notes, 1968 (Box 11)
      - Lectures, 1968
        - Lecture 1 (Box 11)
        - Lectures 2-4 (Box 11)
        - Information Systems (Box 11)
        - Robson Nutrition Lectures (Box 11)
      - Reading Lists and Notes, 1969 (Box 11)
      - Lectures, 1969; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Syllabi, Notes, and Bibliographies, 1970-1971; 1974 (Box 11)
      - Lectures
        - Response to Criticisms of Ecological Anthropology, 1970 (Box 12)
        - circa 1971 (Box 12)
        - circa 1970s, 3 folders (Box 12)
        - The Constituents of Populations, Man as a Dominant Carrying Capacity, circa 1970s (Box 12)
        - The Legal System, circa 1970s (Box 12)
        - Systems and Subsystems, circa 1970s (Box 12)
        - On Adaptive Structure, circa 1970s (Box 12)
        - Lecture Notes-Ecology, circa 1970s (Box 12)
        - Cochran Lecture Notes, circa 1970s (Box 12)
        - Lecture Notes, circa 1972 (Box 12)
      - Syllabus and Lecture Notes, 1976 (Box 12)
      - Lectures
        - Introduction, 1974; 1976 (Box 12)
        - Introduction to Ecological Anthropology, circa 1974 (Box 12)
        - "Cultural Adaptation", circa 1974 (Box 12)
        - Ford Lecture Notes, 1974 (Box 12)
        - Conclusion, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Anthropology 590/627 "Ecological Approaches in Cultural Anthropology II/Prehistoric Human Ecology II"
      - Gregory Bateson, 1969-1971 (Box 12)
      - Syllabi, Lectures, and Notes, 1971; 1975 (Box 12)
      - Cultural Pathology Seminar-Maladaptation, 1971 (Box 12)
      - Lecture-Religion and Adaptation: Ritual, circa 1970s (Box 12)
      - Lecture Notes-High Altitude Adaptation, circa 1970s (Box 12)
      - Handouts on Nutrition, circa 1970s (Box 12)
      - Notes for Lectures, circa 1970s (Box 12)
    - Anthropology 617/648 "Seminar on Ritual"-Reading Lists, Notes, and Handouts, circa 1975-1978; 1983; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Anthropology 626 "Order and Disorder"-Notes and Handouts, 1975; 1977; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Anthropology 689 "Seminar in Ecological Anthropology"
      - Reading List and Notes, 1979 (Box 12)
      - Lectures, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Anthropology 700-Lecture Notes, circa 1970s; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Anthropology 759 "Seminar in Culture and Adaptation"
      - Lectures-Evolution and Culture, 1981; 1983; 1985 (Box 12)
      - Reading Lists and Lecture Notes, 1983 (Box 12)
      - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Religion 201-Guest Lecturer-"Ritual and the Sacred", November 1993 (Box 13)
    - Religion ??? "Religion and Authority"
      - Lecture-Language, Ritual and Authority, An Introduction, January 13, 1992 (Box 13)
      - Lecture-Conclusion, April 20, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Natural Resources 577 "Social Change and Natural Resources"-Lecture-Cultural Perspectives on the Environment, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
    - College Honors 191/University Course 189 "Basic Concepts in the Behavioral Sciences"-Guest Lecturer, 1975; 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - College Course 199-Guest Lecturer, 1976 (Box 13)
    - College Course 320 "Environmental Studies"-Guest Lecturer, 1970 (Box 13)
    - Course Mart Course 335 "The Future of Human Evolution"-Guest Lecturer, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Ecology Seminar
        - Introduction to Talk, February 1968 (Box 13)
        - November Talk, circa 1960s (Box 13)
      - Religion Lectures I and II, 1970 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous Lectures, circa 1972 (Box 13)
      - Doctoral Students, 1967-1979; 1994; 7 folders (Box 18)
      - Student Papers and Course Evaluations, 1969-1996; 10 folders (Box 18)
  - University of London-Senior Colloquium, February 26, 1973 (Box 13)
  - University of Western Ontario-Lectures, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - University of Adelaide
    - Lectures on Religion
      - Introduction, June 24, 1981 (Box 13)
      - Lecture II-The Construction of Time and Eternity in Ritual, 1981 (Box 13)
      - Ritual in The Sacred, The Numinous, and The Holy, July 1981 (Box 13)
      - The Concept of The Sacred, July 1981 (Box 13)
      - Lecture V-The Numinous, The Holy, and The Divine, July 22, 1981 (Box 13)
      - Lecture VI-Adaptation and The Holy, August 5, 1981 (Box 13)
    - Adelaide Colloquium-Sanctity, Truth and Logos, August 12, 1981 (Box 13)
- Consulting
  The Consulting series contains three subseries: Academic Programs, Environmental Projects, and Miscellaneous. The Academic Programs subseries includes material from anthropology department and program reviews that Rappaport participated in for several universities. The Environmental Projects subseries documents Rappaport's belief that anthropological perspectives could contribute to social issues, and includes materials from Rappaport's involvement in nuclear waste issues in Nevada. The Miscellaneous subseries contains correspondence from various other consulting jobs, including the reorganization of the Carnegie Museum of Natural History's anthropology exhibits.
  - Academic Programs
    - Master's Program in Symbolic Anthropology at the University of Western Ontario, circa 1975 (Box 13)
    - Anthropology Department at the University of Colorado, Boulder, 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - Department of Anthropology at the University of Iowa, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
    - Department of Anthropology at Columbia University, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Establishment of an Anthropology Program at the University of Ljubjana (Slovenia), 1988-1993 (Box 13)
    - Anthropology Department at the University of Rochester, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
    - Anthropology Graduate Program at the University of California, Santa Cruz, circa 1990s (Box 13)
  - Environmental Projects
    - Division of Solar Energy, ERDA-Committee to Review ERDA Report 49, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Social Science Research Council-Committee on Biosocial Science, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - U.S. Department of Energy-Decentralized Solar Energy Technology Assessment Program at Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1978-1980 (Box 13)
    - Regarding Energy Systems, circa 1970s (Box 13)
    - Nuclear Waste Disposal Site Location, State of Mississippi-Social Sciences Research Associates, Inc. Peer Review Panel, 1985 (Box 13)
    - State of Nevada-Yucca Mountain Nuclear Waste Repository-Technical Review Committee
      - Correspondence, 1986-1988; 4 folders (Box 13)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1996; 9 folders (Box 14)
      - Correspondence, Memoranda, and Reports, 1986-1990; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Contracts, 1986-1997 (Box 14)
      - Rappaport's Comments on Various Reports, 1988-1994; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Clark County, Nevada-Yucca Mountain Nuclear Waste Repository-Peer Review Committee-Correspondence and Notes, 1991-1995; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Review of Minerals Management Service Programs-Outer Continental Shelf
      - Socioeconomics Panel meeting in Woods Hole, MA, 1988 (Box 15)
      - Socioeconomics Panel meeting in Ft. Meyers, FL, 1989 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence, Notes, and Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 15)
      - Notes and Contract, circa 1988-1996 (Box 15)
    - Tri-County California Oil Study-History of Oil Development in the Santa Barbara Channel-Quality Review Board, circa 1993-1996; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Projects
    - National Science Board-Research in Anthropology, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Carnegie Museum of Natural History-Reorganization of Anthropology Exhibits, circa 1984 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975; 1979; 1991 (Box 15)
- Topical Files
  The last series, Topical Files, documents Rappaport's involvement in the Department of Anthropology, the University of Michigan community, and many of the other groups he belonged to outside of the university (like the American Anthropological Association). The material about the university's Studies in Religion program is particularly rich. Also of note are the records regarding the making of a film about Margaret Mead entitled "Margaret Mead: An Observer Observed."
  - Adaptation and Maladaptation, 1972-1975 (Box 15)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1991 (Box 15)
  - American Anthropological Association (AAA)
    - AAA Convention in Detroit, 1975 (Box 15)
    - Collaborative Conference on Soviet-American Cooperation in Anthropology, 1990-1991; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Committee on Anthropology at Predominately Minority Institutions (CAMPI), 1992; 1995 (Box 15)
    - Fair Practices in Employment of Women, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Harold K. Schneider, 1987 (Box 15)
    - Panel on Disorders in Industrial Societies, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
    - Society for the Anthropology of North America, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Task Force on the Environment, 1991-1992 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1990 (Box 15)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1975; circa 1970s (Box 15)
  - American Ethnological Society, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Anthropological Perspectives, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Richard K. Beardsley, circa 1980s (Box 15)
  - Central States Anthropological Society, 1975-1989 (Box 15)
  - Columbia University, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Committee for the National Institutes for the Environment, 1990-1993 (Box 15)
  - The Creative Faculty, 1990 (Box 15)
  - East-West Center, circa 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - Energy Policy Interest Group, 1981-1983 (Box 15)
  - Morton Fried Memorial, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Hillel Foundation, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Inaugurations
    - Dr. Johnnetta B. Cole-Spelman College, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Dr. Niara Sudarkasa-Lincoln University, 1987 (Box 15)
  - The Institute for Intercultural Studies, 1988-1994; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Institute on Man and Science-Solar Energy Technology Assessment Program, 1978-1980 (Box 15)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1988-1989 (Box 15)
  - Mead Film-"Margaret Mead: An Observer Observed", 1991-1994 (Box 16)
  - The Naropa Institute, 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - National Research Council-Committee on Research Priorities in Tropical Biology, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - National Science Foundation, 1988-1990 (Box 16)
  - Non-Quantifiable Environmental Values, 1977 (Box 16)
  - Papua New Guinea, 1982-1989 (Box 16)
  - Po, 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - PBS Electronic Symposium-"Quality of Life in the Global Environment", 1995 (Box 16)
  - Society for Applied Anthropology (SfAA), 1991-1995 (Box 16)
  - Society for Cultural Anthropology, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Society for the Study of Native Arts and Sciences, 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - Sociobiology, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Substance Abuse-Huron Oaks, 1986 (Box 16)
  - University of Michigan
    - Department of Anthropology
      - Anti-Vietnam War Demonstrations, October 1969 (Box 16)
      - Anthropology 101, 1988; 1996 (Box 16)
      - Anthropology Concentration Program, 1985 (Box 16)
      - "Anthropology: Its Nature and Goals", 1982 (Box 16)
      - Assistant Research Scientists, 1986 (Box 16)
      - Core Courses, 1986-1987; 1991 (Box 16)
      - Departmental Review, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
      - Doctoral Students, 1995 (Box 16)
      - Kai Erikson Visit, 1986 (Box 16)
      - Ethnology Admissions Committee, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Ethnology Program, 1984-1987 (Box 16)
      - Grade Appeal Procedure, 1987 (Box 16)
      - Graduate Program, 1984-1990 (Box 16)
      - Graduate Reading List, 1966 (Box 16)
      - Graduate Reading List-Ethnology, circa 1970s (Box 16)
      - Honors Program in Cultural Anthropology, 1984 (Box 16)
      - Ideas for Teaching and Research, circa 1970s (Box 16)
      - Joint Appointment for Anthropology and the School of Natural Resources and Environment, 1993-1995; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Ray Kelly, 1987-1989 (Box 16)
      - Language Policy, 1987 (Box 16)
      - Proposal for a Graduate Training Program in Ecological Anthropology, 1966-1968 (Box 16)
      - Review Committees, 1985-1988 (Box 16)
      - Undergraduate Program, 1984; 1987 (Box 16)